Chentao Yang

Dr. of astrophysics















As a trained astrophysicist, I have a solid foundation in math and physics. My 10+ years experience in observational astrophysics research has sharpened my data analysis skills and scientific exploration spirits. I'm curious and versed in dissecting complex problems, while maintaining the balance intricate details with big-picture perspectives.

TOOLSET











Shell (Unix/Linux), Julia, FORTRAN, Lang: IDL, Python (NumPy, Pandas, Astropy, Matplotlib, ...), Matlab, Mathematica

VS Code, Jupyter Lab, Git, 上TEX, LyX, **S/W:** Obsidian, Adobe Illustrator, FontLab MS Office (Excel, PowerPoint)...

LANGUAGE

English Full proficiency Mandarin **Native**

French Elementary **Swedish Beginner Beginner Spanish**

INTERESTS



Philosophy, Fiction, Science



👊 Jazz, Classic, Soundtrack



Hiking, Citywalk



🕽 Sci-fi, Indie, Mystery

QUICK FACTS

- **50+ Research Pulications** in top international journals, with 1000+ Citations, several public press releases.
- 5+ GitHub Projects, 50+ Stars (using programming, Bayesian/frequentist statistics, MCMC, graphic design).
- 12+ Oral Presentations in prestigious international conferences (including invited).
- 500+ hours Awarded PI Observing Telescope Time from 30+ proposals.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Postdoctral Researcher in astrophysics (2021-current)

Chalmers tekniska högskola

- Analyzed large interferometric radio data sets of galaxies.
- Creative visualization of astronomical images and related physical parameters.
- Quantified data and interpreted results via mathematical & physical models.
- Leadership in international team for independent complete research projects.

Postdoctral Research Fellow in astrophysics (2017-2021)

European Southern Observatory (ESO)/Joint ALMA Observatory

- Prestigious fellowship in the leading astronomical research center, ESO (Chile).
- Hands-on with the most advanced ground-based observatory, ALMA.
- Independent research from ideas to publications.
- Leading international collaborations.

EDUCATION

PhD in Astrophysics (dual-diploma)

Université Paris-Saclay (2014-2017)

(Top 20 in Academic Ranking of World Universities)

University of Chinese Academy of Sciences (2013-2017)

(Top 70 in Academic Ranking of World Universities)

Master in Astrophysics

Beijing Normal Univesity (2010-2013)

Bachelor in Astronomy

Beijing Normal Univesity (2006-2010)

(Graduate with distinguished honour, at both university and municipality levels)

SKILLS

Team work, Effective communication, Project management, Programming, Creative data visualization, Data intuition, Problem-sovling, Critical thinking, Curiosity

AWARDS

Several Scholarships and Funding Awards

- NAOC (National Astronomical Observatory of China) Scholarship
- National Undergraduate Innovative Test Program Grant (10k CNY)
- ESO Science Support Discretionary Fund (9k EUR)
- The LIA-Origins Short Visit Program Grant (3k EUR)

Fellowship

ESO Fellowship (Chile), 4-year independent research funding